<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet 
href="_assets/recipe.xsl" type="text/xsl"
?>

<recipe lang="en-uk" xmlns:lxslt="http://xml.apache.org/xslt">
<title><![CDATA[Avocado and Pandan Leaf Cakes]]></title>
<description><![CDATA[While the idea of avocado in a dessert may seem rather bizarre initially, it really is delicious and makes an incredibly moist cake. This cake is inspired by the avocado milkshakes I used to have in Ethiopia and in Vietnamese cafes as a teenager. In many parts of Asia, Africa and Latin America avocados are eaten with a sprinkling of sugar as a pudding or even as an ice-cream flavour.

I prefer to use the 'Haas' variety of avocado, also known as a "crocodile pear" due to its dark, wrinkly skin. Hass avocados are rich and buttery tasting and have none of the soapy or bland taste of many of the smooth-skinned varieties.

The pandan leaf is frequently used in puddings and rice dishes in Asia where it lends its delicate, sweet and powdery aroma to dishes. You can find it sold in bundles in many Thai or Asian food shops.

Silicon baking moulds are perfect for this recipe as you do not have to grease them beforehand and once cool the little cakes slide out gracefully onto plates.]]></description>
<source/>
<img></img>
<cuisine>
<style/>
<region/>
<approach/>
</cuisine>
<tags>
<tag>Dessert</tag>
<tag/>
</tags>
<directions xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
<step><![CDATA[Place the milk and the pandan leaf in a saucepan and bring to a gentle simmer. Simmer for 2-3 minutes and then remove from the heat. Set aside to cool for at least 20 minutes allowing the pandan leaf to infuse its flavour into the milk.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Preheat the oven to 110C. Separate the eggs and remove the pandan leaf from the milk.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Place the butter and sugar in a food processor and cream until smooth and fluffy. Add the avocado and egg yolks and process until smooth. Pour in the milk, cream, lime juice and zest and process again until smooth. Add the flour and process briefly until just incorporated.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[If you do not have a food processor, do the first two steps using a hand mixer, then switch to a wooden spoon and stir in the milk, cream and remaining steps by hand.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[In a separate bowl, whisk the egg whites until the form soft peaks. Gently fold the egg whites through the avocado mixture being careful not to deflate your egg whites.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Pour the mold into 8 silicone baking moulds or butter and sugar 8 ceramic ramekins. Place the batter in the oven and bake for 45 minutes to an hour or until the puddings are set and feel springy to the touch.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Allow to cool completely and then turn out onto plates. Serve with tropical fruit, sorbet or ice cream.]]></step>
</directions>
<ingredients xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
        <serves/>
        <group>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>165</quantity>
            <measurement>ml</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[milk]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[whole]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[pandan leaf]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[tied in a knot]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>3</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[eggs]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>30</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[butter]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>180</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[sugar]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[avocado]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[haas or crocodile pear]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>125</quantity>
            <measurement>ml</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[cr\U00e8me fraiche]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[limes]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[juiced]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>90</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[flour]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[plain]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
      </ingredients>
</recipe>
