<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet 
href="_assets/recipe.xsl" type="text/xsl"
?>

<recipe lang="en-uk" xmlns:lxslt="http://xml.apache.org/xslt">
<title><![CDATA[Baked Crêpes with Quick Fig Jam]]></title>
<description><![CDATA[Just about anyone with an East European upbringing will have grown up eating a version of these delicious filled crêpes. Known in Hungarian as 'palacsinta', in Croatia and Serbia as 'palacinka', in Russian as 'blini' and Jewish as 'blintz', these are what children's dreams are made of.]]></description>
<source/>
<img></img>
<cuisine>
<style>Hungary</style>
<region/>
<approach/>
</cuisine>
<tags>
<tag>Dessert</tag>
</tags>
<directions xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
<step><![CDATA[First make the jam by placing the figs, lemon juice and zest and sugar in a large saucepan. Split the vanilla bean lengthwise by running a sharp knife along the centre until it is separated into two halves. Flatten one half of the vanilla bean on a chopping board by placing it cut side up and opening it up gently with your fingers. Scrape the dull, flat side of your knife along the vanilla pod to scrape out the seeds and add them to the pot with the figs and sugar.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Place the saucepan on a low heat and cook the mixture, stirring regularly until the sugar dissolves. Increase the heat and simmer rapidly until the mixture is thick and jam-like, approximately 20-30 minutes. Remove the pan from the heat and set aside to cool.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[To make the crepe dough, sift the dry ingredients into a large mixing bowl. Add the wet ingredients to the dry ingredients and whisk until smooth and there are no lumps in the batter. Check your batter by dipping a metal spoon in the batter and letting the batter run off the spoon - it should be runny but just thick enough to lightly coat the back of the spoon. Set the batter aside for 30 minutes to rest. The batter will thicken slightly.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Meanwhile, make the filling by mixing all the ingredients except the crème fraiche together in a large mixing bowl. Stir with a wooden spoon until thoroughly combined.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Heat a small frying pan or crepe pan on medium-high heat until hot. Swirl in just enough oil to lightly coat the bottom and reduce the heat to medium. With a piece of kitchen towel, lightly wipe out any excess oil, leaving a light coating of oil on the base and all sides. Pour in just enough batter to lightly coat the surface and swirl it around the base. Cook until bubbles appear on the surface of the crepe and the batter is set, then carefully slide a thin spatula underneath and flip the crepe over. Cook for another minute or until the crepe is cooked through and has light brown patches on the underside. Remove to a plate. Continue until you have used up all the batter, wiping the base and sides of the crepe pan in a kitchen towel soaked in a few teaspoons of vegetable oil in between each crepe.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Preheat the oven to 175 C.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Lay a crepe on a worksurface and spread approximately 2 heaping tablespoons of the filling along one side of the crepe. Fold the bottom third of the crepe towards the centre, then fold the left third of the crepe across towards the centre. Place the filled crepe in a buttered ceramic baking dish and continue filling the crepes until you have a single layer in the baking dish.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Spread the crepes with a thin layer of the crème fraiche and continue to place the crepes in the baking dish to make a second layer. Spread the top layer of the crepes with a second layer of the crème fraiche.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Cover the baking dish with aluminium foil and place in the oven. Bake the crepes for 30 minutes. Remove the foil and increase the heat to 225C. Bake for a further 10-15 minutes until golden brown and bubbly.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Remove from the oven and leave to cool for 10 minutes. Cut into sections with a spatula and place on serving dishes. Serve warm with the fig jam.]]></step>
</directions>
<ingredients xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
        <serves/>
        <group>
          <name><![CDATA[Cr\U00eapes]]></name>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>275</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[flour]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[plain]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>3</quantity>
            <measurement>Tbsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[sugar]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>0.25</quantity>
            <measurement>tsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[baking powder]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>l</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[milk]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[whole]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>6</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[eggs]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>125</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[butter]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[melted and cooled slightly]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity/>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[oil]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
        <group>
          <name><![CDATA[Filling]]></name>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>450</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[cheese]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[ricotta]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>250</quantity>
            <measurement>ml</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[goat's curd or other soft mild cheese]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>6</quantity>
            <measurement>Tbsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[cream cheese]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>2</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[egg]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>4</quantity>
            <measurement>Tbsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[sugar]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>250</quantity>
            <measurement>ml</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[cr\U00e8me fraiche]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
        <group>
          <name><![CDATA[Quick Fig Jam]]></name>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>kg</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[figs]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[trimmed ]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[vanilla pod]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[lemon]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[juiced]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>kg</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[sugar]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
      </ingredients>
</recipe>
