<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet 
href="_assets/recipe.xsl" type="text/xsl"
?>

<recipe lang="en-uk" xmlns:lxslt="http://xml.apache.org/xslt">
<title><![CDATA[Banana and Coconut Appam with Jaggery Sugar]]></title>
<description/>
<source/>
<img></img>
<cuisine>
<style>Indian</style>
<region>Kerala</region>
<approach/>
</cuisine>
<tags>
<tag>Dessert</tag>
</tags>
<directions xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
<step><![CDATA[Soak the basmati rice for 4 hours and drain. Place the rice, coconut, banana and coconut milk in a blender or food processor and blend until smooth.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Preheat your oven to 50 C and leave it to warm up for 5 minutes or until just under 50 C., then switch off the heat. Pour the batter into a mixing bowl, add the salt and cover it with foil. Place the bowl into the warm oven and leave it for at least 3 hours or until the batter is slightly bubbly and frothy. Alternatively if it is a hot summer day - leave the batter out on your kitchen work surface for 5 to 6 hours.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Stir the batter to remix it and check the consistency. It should be quite loose and runny when poured from a ladle. If it appears to be too thick and pours in wide ribbons from the ladle, add a little water to thin it out.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Heat a shallow frying pan over medium heat and add approximately 1 tbsp of oil. Swirl the oil around to coat the base. Pour a ladleful of batter over the pan an spread it around the base. Cover the pan with a lid and reduce the heat slightly.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Cook the appam until the underside is golden and crispy, approximately 3 minutes.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Slide out onto a plate and grate some of the jaggery sugar on top. Serve hot.]]></step>
&gt;</directions>
<ingredients xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
        <serves>10</serves>
        <group>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>440</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[rice]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[basmati]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>40</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[coconut]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[grated]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[bananas]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[ripe]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>375</quantity>
            <measurement>ml</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[coconut milk]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>0.5</quantity>
            <measurement>tsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[salt]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity/>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[oil]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[vegetable]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity/>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[jaggery sugar for serving]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
      </ingredients>
</recipe>
