<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet 
href="_assets/recipe.xsl" type="text/xsl"
?>

<recipe lang="en-uk" xmlns:lxslt="http://xml.apache.org/xslt">
<title><![CDATA[Bint Es-Sahn]]></title>
<description><![CDATA[The dough is a little like a yeasted phyllo pastry, which rather than being stretched, is 'slapped' from one hand to the next in a series of fast movements to create paper-thin sheets of dough which are layered in a wide baking dish and scattered with sesame seeds. The technique takes a little practise, but isn't really all that hard once you have got the hang of it.]]></description>
<source/>
<img></img>
<cuisine>
<style>Yemen</style>
<region/>
<approach/>
</cuisine>
<tags>
<tag>Dessert</tag>
</tags>
<directions xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
<step><![CDATA[Sift the flour into a small bowl and sprinkle over the yeast.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Break the eggs into a large, wide mixing bowl and mix with your hands until frothy. Add the oil and water and mix gently until combined. Add the flour and yeast and mix with your hands until it comes together as a dough. Knead for 3-5 minutes until you have a very soft and slightly wet dough. Set aside and leave to rest for 30 minutes.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[With floured hands, re-knead the dough briefly. Sprinkle a work surface generously with flour and tear the dough into approximately 12 pieces about the size of a lime. Place the dough pieces on top of the floured surface, leaving some space between them so they don't stick together.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Take each piece of dough turn it in the flour a few times until it is no longer sticky. Roll it around firmly in the palm of your hand until a smooth, round ball forms. Return each ball of dough to the flour and leave it to rest for 10 minutes.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Preheat the oven to 220 C and grease a large round tart/pie tin. Press down on one of the dough balls with your knuckles to flatten it out and then take it between your hands. Slowly at first, pat the dough firmly back and forth between your hands, 'clapping' it back and forth from palm to palm as if you were applauding.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[As the dough begins to stretch, turn the dough very slightly with each clap so that it stretches into a kind of oval/round shape and try to keep your thumbs closed tightly to your hands to prevent them from piercing holes in the dough. Eventually the dough will start to flap over your hands in a sheet. Continue doing this approximately 25-30 times until the dough is approximately 10-12 inches long and is flapping over half the length of your arm.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Place the dough sheet in the centre of the baking tin and stretch it on all sides pressing it to the sides of the tin with your fingers. Take a spoonful of melted butter and flick it across the dough sheet to splash it across the surface. Then repeat with the remaining dough balls until you have layered them all on top of each other with a splash of melted butter between each one. Leave the last layer of dough unbuttered.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Pour the beaten egg over the top of the final layer of dough and tip the tart tin all around so that it has a coating of egg all over the surface. Tip the excess egg out and discard. Sprinkle the surface of the pastry with the sesame seeds and place it in the oven.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Bake for 15-20 minutes until the top is golden and crispy and the tin sounds hollow when you tap the bottom. Leave to cool slightly and drizzle it generously with honey. Eat with your hands, tearing a section and dipping it into any honey and melted butter that has gathered in the bottom of the tin.]]></step>
</directions>
<ingredients xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
        <serves/>
        <group>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>500</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[flour]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[plain]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>Tbsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[yeast]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[dry]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>3</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[eggs]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>4</quantity>
            <measurement>Tbsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[oil]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>225</quantity>
            <measurement>ml</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[water]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[warm]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>125</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[butter]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[melted]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[eggs]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[beaten]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>handful</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[sesame seeds]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[A small handful of black or plain sesame seeds or a mix of both]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity/>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[Honey for drizzling]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
      </ingredients>
</recipe>
