<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet 
href="_assets/recipe.xsl" type="text/xsl"
?>

<recipe lang="en-uk" xmlns:lxslt="http://xml.apache.org/xslt">
<title><![CDATA[Cambodian Papaya Salad with Peanuts]]></title>
<description><![CDATA[This salad prepared by street vendors in Cambodia is very similar to the 'som tam' salad which is found in Thailand. In Cambodia they use a fermented fish paste called 'prahok' which you can find in the markets sold as a thick, grey sludge. Like other fermented Asian condiments like shrimp paste and fish sauce, prahok is worth cultivating a taste for as it really does add a special note to dishes like this which would be missed without it. If you can't find it, mix together 1 part shrimp paste and 3 parts fish sauce as a substitute.

In Cambodia this salad is given to you in a plastic bag with a makeshift pair of chopsticks to eat it with. A good papaya salad should have a little too much dressing so that the papaya can soak some of the extra up. You know you have the amount right if you manage to dribble dressing down the front of your shirt as you try and eat it.]]></description>
<source/>
<img></img>
<cuisine>
<style>Cambodian</style>
<region/>
<approach/>
</cuisine>
<tags>
<tag>Salad</tag>
</tags>
<directions xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
<step><![CDATA[Place the peanuts in a wok or frying pan over medium heat. Shake the pan regularly for a few minutes until the peanuts become hot and start to release their oil, then with a wooden spoon, stir the peanuts around constantly over the heat until they are golden and well toasted. Place the peanuts in a mortar and pestle and pound until coarsely ground.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Make the dressing by placing the dried shrimp, garlic, chili and palm sugar in a mortar and pestle. Pound the mixture until the palm sugar has dissolved and the ingredients have formed a smooth paste. Add the prahok and lime juice and pound until well mixed. Taste and adjust with more chili, lime juice, sugar and prahok until you have the right balance of hot, sour, sweet and salty.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Add the papaya and beans to the mortar and pestle and pound them a few times to soften. Scrape the vegetables and dressing into a bowl and add the cucumber, tomato and herbs. Toss well to mix.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[To serve, divide the salad between two bowls and scatter with the roasted peanuts.]]></step>
&gt;</directions>
<ingredients xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
        <serves>2</serves>
        <group>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>handful</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[peanuts]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>0.5</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[papaya]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[green]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>2</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[snake beans ]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[or about 8 small green beans cut into bite-sized lengths]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>0.25</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[cucumber]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[peeled]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[tomatoes]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[greem]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>handful</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[mint]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[left whole]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>handful</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[thai basil]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[left whole]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
        <group>
          <name><![CDATA[Dressing]]></name>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>handful</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[small dried shrimp]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>cloves</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[garlic]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[chilli]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[fresh]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>2</quantity>
            <measurement>tsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[sugar]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[palm]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1 - 2</quantity>
            <measurement>Tbsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[prahok]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[(or a pinch of shrimp paste and a splash of fish sauce mixed together)]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[limes]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[juiced]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
      </ingredients>
</recipe>
