<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet 
href="_assets/recipe.xsl" type="text/xsl"
?>

<recipe lang="en-uk" xmlns:lxslt="http://xml.apache.org/xslt">
<title><![CDATA[Chestnut Flour and Pinenut Sablés]]></title>
<description><![CDATA[Sablés are a beautiful, crumbly and buttery kind of shortbread biscuit that are absurdly easy to make. I prefer to form the dough into a log and slice it into rounds rather than rolling it out and using a cookie cutter. It is much easier and also gives your biscuits a slightly more rustic appearance.

Chestnut flour can be found at good Italian and French delis. Ensure that you buy a finely milled flour - some of the stone ground varieties will be too coarse and heavy and will make your sablés quite dense.]]></description>
<source/>
<img></img>
<cuisine>
<style/>
<region/>
<approach/>
</cuisine>
<tags>
<tag>Desserts</tag>
</tags>
<directions xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
<step><![CDATA[Place the flours, sugar and salt in a mixing bowl and stir to combine. Add the butter and work it through the dry ingredients with your fingers until the dough looks like coarse breadcrumbs and starts to stick together. Gather the mixture together in the bowl pressing it firmly with your hands into a ball. The dough should be very firm and compact.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Place the dough on a sheet of baking parchment or waxed paper. With your hands, shape the dough into a log shape the same width as you would like your biscuits to be (about 3.5 inches or so is ideal). Roll the parchment up tightly around the dough and continue to shape the dough with your hands as you roll it to make your log as rounded as possible. Twist the ends of the parchment tightly to seal in the dough.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Place the dough parcel in the freezer for 20 minutes. This will make the dough firm and easier to slice.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Preheat your oven to 170C. Take the dough out of the fridge and slice it with a sharp knife into one inch rounds. Lay the biscuits cut side down on a baking tray lined with parchment and gently press a few pinenuts into the surface of each biscuit.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Place the sablés in the oven and bake for 10-14 minutes or until the sablés are golden. Sablés are soft when they come out of the oven and will firm up and become crumbly as they cool. Allow the biscuits to cool for 10-15 minutes on the baking tray, then remove to a plate.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[The sablés are delicious served on their own or with a coffee granita.]]></step>
&gt;</directions>
<ingredients xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
        <serves/>
        <group>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>55</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[flour]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[chestnut]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>55</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[flour]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[plain]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>50</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[sugar]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[icing]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity/>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[a pinch of salt]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>70</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[butter]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[softened at room temperature]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>2</quantity>
            <measurement>handful</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[pine nuts]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
      </ingredients>
</recipe>
