<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet 
href="_assets/recipe.xsl" type="text/xsl"
?>

<recipe lang="en-uk" xmlns:lxslt="http://xml.apache.org/xslt">
<title><![CDATA[Cranberry and pecan cheesecake]]></title>
<description><![CDATA[I think if you gave most families the choice between a cheesecake and Christmas pudding, they would probably opt for a cheesecake.

There is something so comforting about a creamy cheesecake with its biscuity base - and made with traditional Christmas fruits, it keeps everyone in the festive spirit.

]]></description>
<source/>
<img></img>
<cuisine>
<style/>
<region/>
<approach/>
</cuisine>
<tags>
<tag>Desserts</tag>
<tag/>
</tags>
<directions xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
<step><![CDATA[Put the cranberries in a saucepan with the sugar, orange juice, zest and water, bring to the boil and simmer gently for about 5 minutes; then dilute the cornflour in a little water and stir into the cranberries. Continue simmering for a few minutes until the cranberries are just coated in the 3-4 tablespoons of the thickened liquid, then remove from the heat and leave to    cool to room temperature.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Place the pecans on a tray lined with foil and scatter a couple of tablespoons of sugar from the 120g you need for the cheesecake. Lightly toast under a medium grill, turning them as they are cooking, for 2-3 minutes.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[In a food processor, crush the biscuits to a coarse breadcrumb-like consistency. To do this by hand, put the biscuits in a plastic bag and smash with a rolling pin. Mix the biscuit crumbs with the melted butter.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Line a 14-18cm round or square removable-bottomed cake or deep flan tin (or one of those with a side that unclips) with greaseproof paper. Because the cheescake is soft, the sides of the tin must be detachable. Pack the biscuit mixture into the tin, firming it down with the back of a spoon.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Using a mixing machine or by hand, whip the double cream and sugar until fairly stiff. In a clean bowl, again by machine or hand, soften the cream cheese then add the whipped cream. If you're using softer mascarpone, rather than Philadelphia, you may need about 50g less cream. Carefully fold in half of the cranberry mixture and half the pecans to form a rippled effect. Now spoon the mix on to the biscuit base, leaving the top a bit rough. Leave to set in the fridge for 2-3 hours until firm.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Remove the cheesecake from the tin - you may need to run a hot knife around the edge - then slide it on to a serving dish. Spoon the rest of the cranberry mixture on top and then scatter the rest of the pecans all over.]]></step>
&gt;</directions>
<ingredients xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
        <serves>Serves 8-10
</serves>
        <group>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>150-200</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[fresh cranberries]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity/>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[Grated zest and juice of 1 orange]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>150</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[caster sugar]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>100</quantity>
            <measurement>ml</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[water]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>tsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[cornflour]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>200</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[Hobnobs or digestives]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>80</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[butter]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[melted]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity/>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[For the cheesecake]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>500</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[cream cheese]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[such as mascarpone]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>300</quantity>
            <measurement>ml</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[double cream]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>120</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[caster sugar]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>120</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[pecan nuts]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
      </ingredients>
</recipe>
