<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet 
href="_assets/recipe.xsl" type="text/xsl"
?>

<recipe lang="en-uk" xmlns:lxslt="http://xml.apache.org/xslt">
<title><![CDATA[Farinata]]></title>
<description><![CDATA[the only trick to a good farinata is to get your baking tray good and hot before adding the batter and to be generous with the quantity of olive oil.]]></description>
<source/>
<img></img>
<cuisine>
<style>Italian</style>
<region>Sicilian</region>
<approach/>
</cuisine>
<tags>
<tag>Snack</tag>
</tags>
<directions xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
<step><![CDATA[Make the farinata batter by mixing together the flour, water, salt, pepper and olive oil. Place the batter somewhere warm and leave to ferment for at least 2 hours.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Preheat your oven to 225 and place a large, shallow, rectangular baking tray in the oven to heat up. Skim off any bubbles or froth from the surface of your farinata batter. Remove the tray from the oven and pour in 4-5 tablespoons of olive oil and swirl around until the bottom is well coated. Pour in the farinata batter to the height of 1/4 inch and scatter some of the rosemary on top.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Place the baking tray in the oven and bake for 15 - 20 minutes or until the farinata is set and golden on top and crispy underneath. Remove and allow to cool slightly, then using a metal spatula, carefully slide the farinata out of the pan and scatter with freshly ground pepper to taste. Farinata is typically eaten in wedges, folded over itself. ]]></step>
</directions>
<ingredients xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
        <serves/>
        <group>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>300</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[flour]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[chickpea]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>l</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[water]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[warm]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>65</quantity>
            <measurement>ml</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[oil]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[olive]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity/>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[rosemary]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
      </ingredients>
</recipe>
