<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet 
href="_assets/recipe.xsl" type="text/xsl"
?>

<recipe lang="en-uk" xmlns:lxslt="http://xml.apache.org/xslt">
<title><![CDATA[Injera - Ethiopian 'Sourdough' Crepes]]></title>
<description><![CDATA[If there is one aspect of Ethiopian food that many people are familiar with - it's injera. Sometimes rather sadly compared to 'carpet underlay' due to their bubbly, foam-line texture, these fluffy crepes form the basis of nearly all Ethiopian meals.

Meals in Ethiopia and eaten communally around a large silver platter lined with injera and topped with all manner of wats (stews), sheep's milk cheese and salads. To eat, diners simply start from the outer edges working inwards, tearing pieces of the injera and scooping up food with their hands as they go.

Traditionally injera is made with flour made from a tiny, dark grain called 'teff' however many emigrant Ethiopians use wheat flour with great results. Showit's method of toasting the flour prior to making the injera batter gives the crepes a delicious nutty flavour and also makes them easy to digest.

If you are interesting in making injera with teff flour, you can order it from the Tobia Teff company in London.]]></description>
<source/>
<img></img>
<cuisine>
<style>Ethiopian</style>
<region/>
<approach/>
</cuisine>
<tags>
<tag>Desserts</tag>
</tags>
<directions xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
<step><![CDATA[Place the flour in a large, wide frying pan over medium heat. Toast the flour for 5-6 minutes stirring occasionally until the flour is golden and nutty smelling. Remove from the heat and set aside.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Tip the flour into a bowl and add the water, one third at a time, and mix it well through the flour with your fingers, using your fingers to break up any lumps until you have a smooth but runny crepe-like batter. To check the consistency, hold a handful of the dough over the bowl. It should trickle out of your hands in wide ribbons back into the bowl. Add a little more water if necessary until the desired consistency is reached.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[If using the yeast and salt, add them now and stir them into the batter. Then cover your batter with cling film and leave it somewhere warm to rest for 24 hours. If you aren't using yeast, leave the yeast and salt out and leave your injera batter to ferment for at least 48 hours, ideally 72. Your batter should take on a slightly sour smell and be bubbly and foamy.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Heat a crepe pan or flat, heavy frying pan over medium-high heat. Dip a piece of kitchen roll in the oil or melted butter and rub it over the surface of the pan. Ladle a full measure of the batter into your pan and with a swirling motion, tip your pan so that the batter coats the entire surface of the pan in a thin layer.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Cook the crepe for a minute or two, until the surface is covered with bubbles and the batter is set. Cover the pan with a lid and cook the injera for a minute longer, until the underside is nice and the sides are pulling away from the pan. With a wide spatula, carefully remove the injera from the pan and lay it on a tea towel to cool.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Repeat, oiling the pan in between each injera, until you have used up all the batter. Any leftover batter can be covered and stored in the fridge for a few days.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[When cooled, the injera can be stacked on a place until ready to serve.]]></step>
</directions>
<ingredients xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
        <serves/>
        <group>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>300</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[flour]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[plain]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>l</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[water]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[warm]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>2</quantity>
            <measurement>tsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[yeast]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[dry]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>tsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[salt]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
      </ingredients>
</recipe>
