<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet 
href="_assets/recipe.xsl" type="text/xsl"
?>

<recipe lang="en-uk" xmlns:lxslt="http://xml.apache.org/xslt">
<title><![CDATA[Japanese Ramen]]></title>
<description><![CDATA[Sushi and sashimi aside, Japanese cuisine has some of the best comfort food going. As the weather starts to turn cold and nasty and the economic crisis seems unwilling to loosen its hold, who can say no to a plate of deep-fried katsu in curry sauce or a slurpable bowl of caramel-coloured ramen.

If you want to learn the art of making a good, flavourful soup stock, making ramen is the perfect education. The steps of roasting the bones, simmering the broth overnight and then seasoning, tasting and reducing will quickly turn you from oxo-cube slave into stock-making master.

Just be sure to cook the noodles separately and then add them to the soup before serving. Dried noodles have a tendency to absorb a lot of liquid and if you are making a large quantity you could wind up with 'dry ramen' as the soup absorbs into the ramen noodles.

]]></description>
<source/>
<img></img>
<cuisine>
<style>Japanese</style>
<region/>
<approach/>
</cuisine>
<tags>
<tag>Noodles</tag>
<tag/>
</tags>
<directions xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
<step><![CDATA[Preheat your oven to 180C. Place all the stock ingredients except the rice wine in a large baking dish and mix well so that the meat and vegetables are lightly coated in the oil. Place in the oven and roast for 45 minutes to an hour until the meat and vegetables are well browned and smell delicious.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Tip the ingredients into a large stock pot. Pour the rice wine into the baking dish and scrape with a wooden spoon to pick up any caramelised bits that have stuck to the bottom, then pour the wine and any scrapings into the stock pot. Add water to cover all the meat by an inch and bring to a simmer. As soon as the water comes to a simmer, cover the pot and lower the temperature down to the lowest setting. The soup should only just be bubbling. Leave to simmer for at least 6 hours or overnight. Provided that the temperature is very low and the pot is covered, you do not need to check on your soup during this period - except to admire it's darkening colour and the aromas that will begin to fill your kitchen.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[The same day that you make the soup, prepare the marinade for the pork. Combine the ginger, garlic, onions, soy sauce, mirin, rice wine, sugar and salt in a blender or food processor and blend until smooth. Place the pork in a small container and pour the marinade over, turning the pork several times and massaging the marinade well into the pork. Cover with cling film and place in the fridge to marinate overnight.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[The next day switch the heat off and allow the soup to cool slightly. Strain the stock through a colander and discard all the meat and vegetables. Place the stock in the fridge and chill for several hours.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Meanwhile, braise the pork for the soup by removing it from the marinade and patting dry with kitchen roll. Reserve the marinade. Heat the vegetable oil in a wide, deep sauté pan on high heat. Add the pork and sear it for a minute per side, turning it with tongs until it has a light, golden crust on all sides. Pour in the reserved marinade and add just enough water to submerge the pork to a depth of one-third. Cover tightly with a lid and bring the liquid in the pan to a simmer, then reduce to a gentle simmer and simmer for two hours, turning the pork once or twice. The pork should be tender when poked with a knife tip. Remove the pork from the pan, place on a cutting board and cover loosely with foil. Leave the pork to rest for 15 minutes.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Remove your stock from the fridge and skim off any fat that has solidified from the surface. Bring the soup to a simmer and tip in the braising juices from the pork. Taste the stock. If it tastes weak, bring to a boil and reduce the stock by one-quarter to a third and taste again. If it tastes full-bodied, season it to taste with 1-2 tsp of salt. Keep warm while you prepare the noodles.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Bring a pot of water to the boil and cook the noodles according to the instructions on the package. Drain and divide the noodles between wide soup bowls. Slice the pork into 1 inch thick slices and place 2-3 slices on top of each bowl of noodles. Ladle a generous quantity of stock over the noodles and pork and top with a sprinkling of spring onion greens.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Serve hot.]]></step>
</directions>
<ingredients xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
        <serves>5-6</serves>
        <group>
          <name><![CDATA[Soup Stock]]></name>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>2</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[carrots]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>2</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[onions]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[peeled and halved]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>head</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[garlic]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[unpeeled with the top inch sliced off to reveal the tips of the cloves]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>kg</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[assorted bones]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[ideally pork and/or beef bones]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>250</quantity>
            <measurement>ml</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[rice wine]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[or sherry]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
        <group>
          <name><![CDATA[Braised Pork]]></name>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>2</quantity>
            <measurement>kg</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[piece of boneless pork loin]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[fat and skin removed and tied into a nice round parcel with twine]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>5</quantity>
            <measurement>cm</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[ginger]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[peeled]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>2</quantity>
            <measurement>cloves</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[garlic]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[peeled]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>2</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[spring onions]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[white parts only]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>5</quantity>
            <measurement>Tbsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[soy sauce]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[light]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>5</quantity>
            <measurement>Tbsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[mirin]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>65</quantity>
            <measurement>ml</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[rice wine]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[or sherry]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>0.5</quantity>
            <measurement>tsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[sugar]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>2</quantity>
            <measurement>tsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[oil]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
        <group>
          <name><![CDATA[For Serving The Soup]]></name>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity/>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[fresh ramen]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[or dried]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>3</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[spring onions]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[greens]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
      </ingredients>
</recipe>
