<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet 
href="_assets/recipe.xsl" type="text/xsl"
?>

<recipe lang="en-uk" xmlns:lxslt="http://xml.apache.org/xslt">
<title><![CDATA[Jingala - Armenian Flatbread Stuffed with Wild Greens]]></title>
<description><![CDATA[Jingala is a famous village bread made from a sparkling water dough and stuffed with handfuls of lightly seasoned wild herbs and greens picked from the forests and mountain riverbeds. Armenian winters are long and cold so Armenians eat wild herbs and greens in abundance in spring as a tonic to purify their blood and chase off any sluggishness.

]]></description>
<source/>
<img></img>
<cuisine>
<style>Armenia</style>
<region/>
<approach/>
</cuisine>
<tags>
<tag>Pie</tag>
</tags>
<directions xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
<step><![CDATA[To make the dough, combine the flour and salt in a bowl and stir to combine. Make a well the centre of the flour and pour in the sparkling water and oil. Stir until it forms a shaggy dough, then turn out on to a lightly floured work surface and knead for 10 minutes, adding flour as needed to keep the dough from sticking, until the dough is smooth and elastic.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Pour a drizzle of oil into a clean bowl and rub it all along the bottom and sides with your hands. Place the dough in the bowl and turn one or two times to coat, then cover the bowl with cling film and set aside to rest.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Finely chop the greens and herbs and place in a bowl with the onion and chili flakes. Add just enough oil to lightly coat the oil and season to taste with salt and pepper. Taste the greens - they should be slightly over seasoned with the chili, salt and pepper to keep the flavour strong once inside the dough.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Heat a heavy cast iron or nonstick pan on medium-high heat.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Tear the dough into lime sized pieces and working one at a time, roll the dough very thin, about 1/8 of an inch into a round disc. Cover the disk with a generous amount of the greens and carefully gather the sides together over the greens, pinching them closed with your fingers to form a seal. Roll lightly with a rolling pin to flatten.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Pour a small quantity of oil into the pan and brush across the base with a piece of kitchen towel. Place the flatbread in the pan and cook for 3-4 minutes per side until golden on both sides and the dough is cooked through.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Repeat with the remaining dough and filling and serve the flatbreads warm.]]></step>
&gt;</directions>
<ingredients xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
        <serves>6</serves>
        <group>
          <name><![CDATA[For The Dough]]></name>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>275</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[flour]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[strong]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>2</quantity>
            <measurement>tsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[salt]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>200</quantity>
            <measurement>ml</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[sparkling water]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>3</quantity>
            <measurement>Tbsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[oil]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[sunflower]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
        <group>
          <name><![CDATA[Wild Green Stuffing]]></name>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>4</quantity>
            <measurement>handful</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[mixed wild greens and herbs such as sorrel]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[nettles]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[onions]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[finely minced]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>0.5</quantity>
            <measurement>tsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[chillies]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[dried]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity/>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[a drizzle of olive oil to lightly coat the greens]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
      </ingredients>
</recipe>
