<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet 
href="_assets/recipe.xsl" type="text/xsl"
?>

<recipe lang="en-uk" xmlns:lxslt="http://xml.apache.org/xslt">
<title><![CDATA[KulichRussian Easter Bread with Saffron]]></title>
<description><![CDATA[Kulich is traditionally baked in coffee cans, however Katrina baked hers in small unglazed flour pots which looks festive and colourful when brought to the table. Kulich is normally served with the Russian accompaniment of 'pashka' a ricotta-like set cheese with candied fruit, however it is equally delicious spread with cream cheese and honey.

]]></description>
<source/>
<img></img>
<cuisine>
<style>Russian</style>
<region/>
<approach/>
</cuisine>
<tags>
<tag>Desserts</tag>
</tags>
<directions xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
<step><![CDATA[In a small saucepan, gently warm the milk until it reaches body temperature. Remove from the heat, add the saffron threads and leave to infuse for a few minutes. Pour the milk and saffron mixture into a large mixing bowl and add the yeast and 1 tsp of the sugar and whisk until dissolved. Stir in approximately 1/2 cup of the flour and let stand.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Toss the chopped mixed fruit with the ground spices and a few pinches of flour.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Using a hand mixer on medium speed, cream the butter and sugar until light and fluffy, then add the eggs one at a time, beating well after each egg until well incorporated.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Add the beaten egg mixture, the dried fruit and the salt into the milk and flour mixture and stir well until the mixture comes together into a dough. Turn the dough out onto a lightly floured worksurface and knead for approximately 7-10 minutes, adding a sprinkling of extra flour as necessary to keep the dough from being too sticky.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Pour the vegetable oil into a large, clean bowl and rub all over the surface of the inside of the bowl. Place the dough in the bowl and turn it over once or twice until the surface of the dough is lightly covered in the oil. This will keep it moist during rising. Cover the bowl with a damp tea towel and place in a warm place to rise for an hour or until doubled in size.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Grease four small unglazed 15cm flower pots with butter. Punch down the dough to deflate it and divide it into 4 balls. Place a ball of dough into each flourpot and leave to rise for a further 30 minutes.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Preheat the oven to 180C. Place the flour pots in the oven and bake for approximately 30 minutes or until lightly golden and hollow sounding when you tap on the surface of the bread.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Serve warm in thick cut slices.]]></step>
</directions>
<ingredients xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
        <serves/>
        <group>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>500</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[flour]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[plain]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>Tbsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[yeast]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[fresh]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>185</quantity>
            <measurement>ml</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[milk]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>pinch</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[saffron]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>125</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[sugar]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>3</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[eggs]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>110</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[butter]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[at room temperature]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>150</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[dried fruit]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[mixed chopped finely (raisins]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1/2</quantity>
            <measurement>tsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[salt]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>tsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[ground cardamom]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1/2</quantity>
            <measurement>tsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[ground cinnamon]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1/4</quantity>
            <measurement>tsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[ground nutmeg]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1/2</quantity>
            <measurement>tsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[oil]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
      </ingredients>
</recipe>
