<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet 
href="_assets/recipe.xsl" type="text/xsl"
?>

<recipe lang="en-uk" xmlns:lxslt="http://xml.apache.org/xslt">
<title><![CDATA[Lamb Meatballs with Saffron, Cinnamon and Almond Sauce]]></title>
<description/>
<source/>
<img></img>
<cuisine>
<style>Iranian</style>
<region/>
<approach/>
</cuisine>
<tags>
<tag>With Bread</tag>
<tag/>
</tags>
<directions xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
<step><![CDATA[Place the onion into the bowl of a food processor and process until finely chopped. Add the lamb and thyme leaves and pulse until well blended. Add the egg, salt and pepper to taste and pulse again until well mixed together. Note: If you don't have a food processor, you can do this by hand in a mixing bowl, just mince the onion finely before mixing it with the other ingredients.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Place the flour in a shallow bowl. With your hands, take some of the lamb mixture and roll it between your palms to form a golf ball-sized ball. Roll the ball in the flour and tap off the excess. Place the floured ball on a large, clean plate. Repeat until you have used up all the lamb mince mixture.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Cover with cling film and place in the fridge to firm up for 30 minutes before frying.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[In a large, wide frying pan, heat the olive oil on medium-high heat. When the oil is hot but not smoking, add the meatballs and fry until well browned on all sides. Remove the meatballs with tongs or a slotted spoon and place on a clean plate.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Make the sauce by adding the 2 tablespoons of oil to the pan. Add the garlic and saute briefly. Add the tomatoes and stir with a wooden spoon to break up. Adjust heat so that tomatoes reach a gentle simmer. Add the meatballs to the tomatoes and stir once gently so that they are nestled and coated in the tomato mixture. Leave to simmer gently for 25 minutes.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[In the bowl of a food processor, place the cinnamon, parsley, and almonds. Using the side of a spoon, crush the saffron threads against the side of the cup and then add the saffron and water. Pulse briefly until the almonds are coarsely ground. Be careful not to overprocess or you'll have almond 'peanut butter'. If you do not have a food processor, chop the almonds finely and stir in the cinnamon, parsley and saffron.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Add the almond mixture to the simmering meatballs and stir gently to mix through. Continue to simmer gently for 5 minutes. The sauce should be thick and cling to the meatballs.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Spoon meatballs and sauce into a bowl and serve.]]></step>
</directions>
<ingredients xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
        <serves/>
        <group>
          <name><![CDATA[For the Meatballs]]></name>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[onion]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>handful</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[parsley]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[minced]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>500</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[lamb]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[minced]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[egg]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>55</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[flour]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[plain]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>4</quantity>
            <measurement>Tbsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[olive oil]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
        <group>
          <name><![CDATA[For the Sauce]]></name>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>2</quantity>
            <measurement>Tbsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[olive oil]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>2</quantity>
            <measurement>cloves</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[garlic]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[minced]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>tin</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[tomatoes]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[peeled]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>tsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[cinnamon]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[ground]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>handful</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[parsley]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>100</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[almonds]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[blanched]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>pinch</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[saffron threads]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
      </ingredients>
</recipe>
