<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet 
href="_assets/recipe.xsl" type="text/xsl"
?>

<recipe lang="en-uk" xmlns:lxslt="http://xml.apache.org/xslt">
<title><![CDATA[Lamingtons]]></title>
<description/>
<source/>
<img></img>
<cuisine>
<style>Australian</style>
<region/>
<approach/>
</cuisine>
<tags>
<tag>Desserts</tag>
</tags>
<directions xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
<step><![CDATA[To make the sponge cake, preheat the oven to 170 C.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Place the eggs and sugar into the bowl of a stand mixer or into a mixing bowl if using a hand-held beater. Beat the mixture for 8-10 minutes on medium-high speed until thick and pale and tripled in volume. Sift the flour three times and gently fold through the egg mixture using a metal spoon using a gentle lifting and folding motion. This will help keep the cake light and moist and avoid deflating your whipped up eggs. Add the butter and fold through 3-4 times.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Pour the mixture into a greased 7 inch square cake tin and place in the oven to bake for 13-16 minutes or until the cake is springy to the touch and lightly golden. Remove from the oven and allow to cool for 5 minutes, then invert the cake onto a wire rack and leave overnight to cool and harden slightly.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Place the sponge cake onto a chopping board and cut into 2 1/2 inch squares with a sharp knife. Place the cubes well spaced in the freezer for 1-2 hours until firm.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Make the icing by sifting the sugar and cocoa together and mixing with the milk and melted butter to make a smooth icing of pourable consistency. Place the cubes on a fork and dip into the icing to coat (you can also do this using your fingers or by ladling the icing over the lamingtons in batches and turning them.) Allow the excess icing to drip off and then roll the lamingtons in the coconut. Return the lamingtons to the rack then place them in the fridge for an hour to set and help the coconut to stick to the frosting.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[For true authenticity, serve lamingtons with a flat white - the antipodean version of a latte.]]></step>
</directions>
<ingredients xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
        <serves/>
        <group>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>6</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[eggs]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>150</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[sugar]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>150</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[flour]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[plain]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>60</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[butter]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[melted]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
        <group>
          <name><![CDATA[Chocolate Icing]]></name>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>400</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[sugar]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[icing]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>50</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[cocoa powder]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>45</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[butter]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[melted]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>125</quantity>
            <measurement>ml</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[milk]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[hot]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>200</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[coconut]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[dessicated]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
      </ingredients>
</recipe>
