<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet 
href="_assets/recipe.xsl" type="text/xsl"
?>

<recipe lang="en-uk" xmlns:lxslt="http://xml.apache.org/xslt">
<title><![CDATA[Parathas Stuffed with Roast Cauliflower]]></title>
<description><![CDATA[Parathas - flatbreads that have been stuffed with a savoury filling - are like India's answer to the sandwich. These parathas contain a nutty, spiced roast cauliflower filling and are one of my favourite kind of parathas to make.]]></description>
<source/>
<img></img>
<cuisine>
<style>Indian</style>
<region/>
<approach/>
</cuisine>
<tags>
<tag>Bread</tag>
<tag/>
</tags>
<directions xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
<step><![CDATA[Preheat the oven to 190 C]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Toast the spices for the stuffing by placing them in a dry frying pan over medium-low heat. Shaking the pan frequently, toast the spices for 3-4 minutes or until fragrant. Grind the spices to a fine powder in a spice grinder or a mortar and pestle.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Place the spices, cauliflower, garlic, honey, oil and salt in a roasting tin and toss well to mix. Place in the oven and roast for 20-30 minutes, stirring occasionally until the cauliflower is nutty and browned. Remove from the oven and leave to cool, then stir in the amchoor powder and coriander.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[While the cauliflower is roasting, make the dough by combining the flour, milk, yoghurt, butter and salt in a large mixing bowl. Stir it with a wooden spoon until it comes together as a dough, then turn the dough out onto a lightly floured worksurface and knead for 10 minutes until the dough is smooth and elastic. Divide the dough into 6 balls of equal size, cover them in cling film and set them aside to rest in the fridge for 30 minutes.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Working with one ball of dough at a time, take a ball of dough and flatten it out to a thickness of about 1/2 an inch using either your hands or a rolling pin. Spread 2-3 tablespoons of the filling onto the dough leaving a margin of about an inch on all sides.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Gather the edges of the dough towards the centre and press down gently but firmly with your hands to seal in the filling and reseal the edges of the dough. Flatten the dough out gently with your hands being careful not to break the dough and spill the filling, until it is approximately 1/2 inch thick. Repeat with all the dough balls, layering them between sheets of parchment paper to keep them from sticking to each other until you are ready to cook them.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Heat a large frying pan on medium high heat and add approximately 1 tbsp of oil. Swirl the oil around to coat the base. Add one of the parathas and cook it for approximately 4-5 minutes per side until it is nice and golden and crisp on both sides and the filling is heated through.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Cut each paratha into quarters and serve immediately.]]></step>
</directions>
<ingredients xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
        <serves>4-6</serves>
        <group>
          <name><![CDATA[Bread]]></name>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>250</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[flour]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[plain]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>70</quantity>
            <measurement>ml</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[milk]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>125</quantity>
            <measurement>ml</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[yogurt]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>Tbsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[butter]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[salted]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
        <group>
          <name><![CDATA[Stuffing]]></name>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>Tbsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[coriander seeds]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>Tbsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[cumin seeds]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>tsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[fenugreek seeds]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>6</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[black peppercorns]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[cauliflower]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[broken into small florets and finely chopped]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>3</quantity>
            <measurement>cloves</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[garlic]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[minced]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>2</quantity>
            <measurement>tsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[honey]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>3</quantity>
            <measurement>Tbsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[vegetable oil]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>Tbsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[salt]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>tsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[amchoor]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>handful</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[coriander leaves]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[finely chopped]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
      </ingredients>
</recipe>
