<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet 
href="_assets/recipe.xsl" type="text/xsl"
?>

<recipe lang="en-uk" xmlns:lxslt="http://xml.apache.org/xslt">
<title><![CDATA[Rice Flour and Chickpea Pancakes with Tamarind Sauce]]></title>
<description><![CDATA[This delicious snack is prepared in the streets of Burma where it is cooked in shallow terracotta pots over a charcoal fire and eaten with tamarind sauce. Rice flour is easily available in Asian and Indian grocery stores and is a great alternative to wheat flour for people with gluten allergies. Just be sure to buy plain rice flour and not 'sticky' or glutinous rice flour]]></description>
<source/>
<img></img>
<cuisine>
<style>Burmese</style>
<region/>
<approach/>
</cuisine>
<tags>
<tag>Snack</tag>
</tags>
<directions xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
<step><![CDATA[To make the tamarind sauce, place the tamarind pulp in a small bowl and pour over the boiling water. Set aside for 20 minutes, then rub the pulp between your fingers until the texture of the water is thick - similar to ketchup.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Pour the tamarind and water through a fine mesh strainer with a bowl underneath to catch the liquid. Press down on the tamarind fibres to extract as much flavour and liquid as possible, then discard the tamarind pulp.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Combine the tamarind water, palm sugar and fish sauce in a small, heavy based saucepan on medium heat. Bring to a gentle simmer, stirring occasionally until all the palm sugar has dissolved. Continue to simmer for a further 3-5 minutes or until the sauce has thickened slightly. Remove from the heat, stir in the coriander and set aside.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Combine the rice flour and salt in a bowl and add just enough water to make a thick batter. Whisk well so that there are no lumps.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Heat the oil in a small, non-stick or cast-iron frying pan on medium heat. When the oil is hot, ladle some of the batter into the frying pan. Cook until bubbles appear on the top. Scatter some chickpeas across the surface, pressing them gently into the pancake, then flip over and cook for another 2-3 minutes on the other side. Repeat with the remaining batter, keeping the pancakes warm in the oven.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Serve on a large platter with the tamarind sauce on the side for dipping.]]></step>
&gt;</directions>
<ingredients xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
        <serves/>
        <group>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>400</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[flour]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[rice]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>0.25</quantity>
            <measurement>tsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[salt]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity/>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[water]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>2</quantity>
            <measurement>tsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[oil]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>handful</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[chickpeas]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[cooked]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
        <group>
          <name><![CDATA[Tamarind Sauce]]></name>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>60</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[tamarind pulp]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>250</quantity>
            <measurement>ml</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[water]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[boiling]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>6</quantity>
            <measurement>Tbsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[sugar]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[palm]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>4</quantity>
            <measurement>Tbsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[fish sauce]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>handful</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[coriander leaves]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[finely chopped]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
      </ingredients>
</recipe>
