<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet 
href="_assets/recipe.xsl" type="text/xsl"
?>

<recipe lang="en-uk" xmlns:lxslt="http://xml.apache.org/xslt">
<title><![CDATA[Roast Cauliflower Mash]]></title>
<description><![CDATA[I love roast cauliflower and have had the idea of this recipe floating in my mind for months. I finally got around to making it and it tastes just as nutty and delicious as I'd hoped.]]></description>
<source/>
<img></img>
<cuisine>
<style/>
<region/>
<approach/>
</cuisine>
<tags>
<tag>vegetable side</tag>
</tags>
<directions xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
<step><![CDATA[Place the cauliflower pieces in a baking dish in a single layer and drizzle over the olive oil and sprinkle generously with salt and pepper. Toss a few times to coat the cauliflower in the oil and seasonings and place the tray in the oven. Roast for 25-35 minutes, until the cauliflower is tender when pierced with a knife and the edges of the cauliflower have turned golden and slightly crispy.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Place the cauliflower in a food processor and puree until smooth. If you don't have a food processor, try using a potato ricer or else a vigorous session with a potato masher should yield reasonably good results.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[With the motor of your food processor running, slowly pour in the melted butter until it is all incorporated. Alternatively, if mashing by hand, whip the melted butter through the mash with a spoon.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Taste and season to taste with more salt and pepper. Serve hot.]]></step>
</directions>
<ingredients xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
        <serves>4</serves>
        <group>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[cauliflower]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[broken into small florets]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>Tbsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[oil]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[olive]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>6-8</quantity>
            <measurement>Tbsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[butter]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[melted]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
      </ingredients>
</recipe>
