<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet 
href="_assets/recipe.xsl" type="text/xsl"
?>

<recipe lang="en-uk" xmlns:lxslt="http://xml.apache.org/xslt">
<title><![CDATA[Roast Butternut Squash, Onion and Garlic Soup]]></title>
<description><![CDATA[I love to serve this soup quite thick and velvety but you can thin it by simply adding more stock, milk or cream. If you happen to have some truffle oil in your cupboard, a little drizzle on top would be a perfect finish.

]]></description>
<source/>
<img></img>
<cuisine>
<style/>
<region/>
<approach/>
</cuisine>
<tags>
<tag>Soup</tag>
<tag/>
</tags>
<directions xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
<step><![CDATA[Preheat an oven to 200 C.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Place the squash halves, onion and garlic in a roasting tin that fill fit all the vegetables snugly in a single layer. Tuck the thyme sprigs amongst the vegetables and drizzle with the olive oil. Scatter the chile flakes over top and season generously with the salt and pepper]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Cover the baking dish tightly with foil and roast the vegetables for an hour or until very soft. Allow to cool slightly, then scoop the squash and onion flesh from their skins with a large spoon and place them into the bowl of a food processor. Squeeze the head of garlic so that the cloves 'ooze' out and add them to the squash and onion. Process in the food processor until smooth.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Place the squash purée in a soup pot and whisk in the stock, milk or cream until it reaches your desired consistency. Warm the soup gently until heated through and check the seasoning for salt and pepper.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Serve ladelled into bowls with a dollop of crème fraîche and a scattering of pine nuts on top.]]></step>
&gt;</directions>
<ingredients xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
        <serves/>
        <group>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[squash]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[butternut]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[onion]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[halved with the skin left on]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>head</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[garlic]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[with just the pointy top sliced off]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>4</quantity>
            <measurement>sprigs</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[thyme]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>5</quantity>
            <measurement>Tbsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[oil]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[olive]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>tsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[chili flakes]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
        <group>
          <name><![CDATA[Optional]]></name>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity/>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[stock]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[milk and/or cream to thin]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity/>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[cr\U00e8me fra\U00eeche and toasted pine nuts to serve]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
      </ingredients>
</recipe>
