<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet 
href="_assets/recipe.xsl" type="text/xsl"
?>

<recipe lang="en-uk" xmlns:lxslt="http://xml.apache.org/xslt">
<title><![CDATA[Tlayudas with Chile-Marinated Pork, Beans and Fried Egg with Smoked Chile Salsa]]></title>
<description><![CDATA[Tlayudas are a kind of Mexican pizza made from corn tortillas which are crisped over charcoal and covered with any number of toppings. You can spot a good tlayuda stall as cars will literally park in the middle of the street in front to run in and pick up some tlayudas to take home.]]></description>
<source/>
<img></img>
<cuisine>
<style>Mexican</style>
<region/>
<approach/>
</cuisine>
<tags>
<tag>Snack</tag>
</tags>
<directions xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
<step><![CDATA[First make the beans by placing the beans, onion and garlic in a large pot with the litre of water. Bring to a simmer and simmer gently for an hour or until the beans are tender. On a barbecue, griddle pan or under your oven grill, roast the jalapenos until they are charred and blackened all over. Scrape off the skins with a knife and discard. Remove the stems and seeds from the chilies and place in a blender or food processor with the cooked beans, onion and garlic. Blend, adding just enough of the bean cooking liquid to make a smooth puree.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Warm the oil on medium heat in a heavy frying pan and add the bean puree. Cook the puree, stirring frequently, until the puree is thickened and paste-like. Taste and season with salt, then set aside.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Marinate the pork by placing the chilies in a heat-proof bowl and covering with the boiling water. Leave the chilies to soak for 20 minutes or until they are soft. Meanwhile toast the spices in a dry frying pan over medium-low heat for a few minutes until fragrant.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Place the chilies along with 1/3 of the soaking liquid in a blender along with the spices, vinegar, garlic and a generous pinch of salt. Blend until reasonably smooth and pour over the sheets of pork. Place in the fridge to marinate for an hour or up to overnight.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[To make the salsa, roast the chilies, tomatillos and garlic on a barbecue, griddle pan or under your oven grill, roast the jalapenos until they are charred and fragrant. Place the ingredients in a blender or food processor along with the water and process until smooth. Season with salt to taste.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[To make the tlayudas, preheat a barbecue or your oven to 225C. Spread the tortillas with the bean puree and top with some of the grated cheese. Place the tortillas directly on your barbecue or in your oven and bake for 5 minutes or until crisp.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Meanwhile remove the pork from the marinade and grill on the barbecue or in a hot griddle pan until cooked through. Heat the oil in a frying pan and fry the eggs until done to your liking.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Now you have a few options. You can place the eggs inside the tlayudas and fold them over in half and place the grilled strips of pork on top. You can place everything inside and fold the tlayudas in half. Or you can leave the tlayudas open like a pizza and place the egg and pork on top.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Serve the tlayudas hot with the smoked chile salsa. Tlayudas are traditionally eaten with your hands, tearing from the outside inwards and scooping up the toppings. Yum!]]></step>
&gt;</directions>
<ingredients xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
        <serves/>
        <group>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>batch</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[corn tortilla]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>handful</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[cheese]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[grated]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>6</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[eggs]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
        <group>
          <name><![CDATA[For The Beans]]></name>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>170</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[black beans]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[dried]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[onion]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[finely chopped]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>5</quantity>
            <measurement>cloves</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[garlic]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[finely chopped]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>l</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[water]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>2</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[chilies]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[jalapeno]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>2</quantity>
            <measurement>tsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[oil]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
        <group>
          <name><![CDATA[For The Chile-Marinated Pork (Cecina)]]></name>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>6</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[chilies]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[dried guajillo]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>500</quantity>
            <measurement>ml</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[water]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[boiling]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>0.5</quantity>
            <measurement>tsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[black peppercorns]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>2</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[cloves]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>3</quantity>
            <measurement>cm</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[cinnamon]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>125</quantity>
            <measurement>ml</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[vinegar]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[cider]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>7</quantity>
            <measurement>cloves</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[garlic]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>500</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[pork loin]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[sliced very thinly into long sheets]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
        <group>
          <name><![CDATA[For The Smoked Chile Salsa]]></name>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>3</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[chilies]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[dried pasilla or chipotle ]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>7</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[tomatillos]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>2</quantity>
            <measurement>cloves</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[garlic]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>65</quantity>
            <measurement>ml</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[water]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
      </ingredients>
</recipe>
