<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet 
href="_assets/recipe.xsl" type="text/xsl"
?>

<recipe lang="en-uk" xmlns:lxslt="http://xml.apache.org/xslt">
<title><![CDATA[Turkish Fig and Coffee Bread]]></title>
<description/>
<source/>
<img></img>
<cuisine>
<style>Turkish</style>
<region/>
<approach/>
</cuisine>
<tags>
<tag>Bread</tag>
</tags>
<directions xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
<step><![CDATA[To make the dough, mix the water and yeast together until dissolved and let stand for 5 minutes.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Place the water and dissolved yeast in a large mixing bowl and gradually mix in half the flour to form a loose, sponge-like dough. Cover with a damp tea towel and place in a warm spot to rise for an hour.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[While the sponge dough is rising, place the chopped figs in a bowl and pour over the espresso. Set aside to let the figs macerate in the coffee - they will absorb all the coffee and plump up. Puree two thirds of the figs along with the espresso and set aside.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Add the sea salt, olive oil and half of the fig puree to the dough and using a wooden spoon, mix in approximately a half a cup of flour at a time until the dough is too dense to stir with the spoon. Add the remaining fig puree and chopped figs and stir until the dough is uniform. Remove to a work surface and knead for approximately 10 minutes incorporating the remaining flour until the dough is smooth and manageable.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Place the dough in a lightly oiled bowl and set aside to rise for an hour or until doubled in size.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Preheat your oven to 210C. Divide the dough into 2 oval log shapes on baking parchment or a 2 well oiled baking trays. Cut diagonal slashes in the dough and brush each loaf with olive oil, tugging apart the slashes slightly to separate them. Allow the loaves to rise for 15-20 minutes, then place them in the preheated oven.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Bake the loaves for 15-20 minutes, swapping their positions in your oven (i.e. moving the one on the bottom shelf to the top and the top to the bottom) or until the bread is golden and sounds hollow when tapped with your fingers. Remove and allow to cool.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Slice and serve with cheese, honey, quince jam or clotted cream.]]></step>
&gt;</directions>
<ingredients xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
        <serves/>
        <group>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>350</quantity>
            <measurement>ml</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[water]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[warm]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>2</quantity>
            <measurement>tsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[yeast]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[dry]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>225</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[flour]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[plain]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>225</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[figs]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[dried]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>2</quantity>
            <measurement>shots</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[espresso]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>1</quantity>
            <measurement>Tbsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[sea salt]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>125</quantity>
            <measurement>ml</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[oil]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[olive]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>325</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[flour]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[plain]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
      </ingredients>
</recipe>
