<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet 
href="_assets/recipe.xsl" type="text/xsl"
?>

<recipe lang="en-uk" xmlns:lxslt="http://xml.apache.org/xslt">
<title><![CDATA[XO Sauce]]></title>
<description><![CDATA[A kind of dried seafood and pork chili jam originating from Hong Kong, a few spoonfuls of XO sauce added to stir fried vegetables (shown here with garlic sprouts), noodles or fried rice adds a spicy, salty and sweet kick that is irresistible.

Composed of dried scallops, dried shrimp and roast pork belly slowly cooked in a mixture of sugar, garlic, shallots and lots of dried chilies, XO sauce can be easily purchased in jars from Chinese supermarkets, but it is much nicer and more fun to make your own. With all the recent negative press about Chinese food scandals and tainted foodstuffs, making your own batch ensures that you can use the best quality ingredients.

The dried scallops or 'colpoy' needed to make XO sauce can be purchased behind the counter at the New Loon Moon Supermarket on Gerrard St in Chinatown.]]></description>
<source/>
<img></img>
<cuisine>
<style>Chinese</style>
<region/>
<approach/>
</cuisine>
<tags>
<tag>Sauce</tag>
</tags>
<directions xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
<step><![CDATA[Place the scallops in a bowl and cover with cold water. Place the scallops in the fridge overnight to rehydrate them. Drain and place the soaked scallops in a steamer. Steam the scallops for 2 hours or until they are tender when pierced with a skewer. Set aside to cool then shred the scallops coarsely with your fingers.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Meanwhile preheat your oven to 210C. Place the pork belly in a baking dish and roast for 35 minutes or until tender and cooked through. Allow to cool, then remove the skin and finely chop the meat.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[While the pork and scallops are cooking, place the chilies and dried shrimp in a small bowl, cover with warm water and leave to soak for 30 minutes, then drain.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Warm the vegetable oil in a wok and add the dried shrimp, chilies, shallots, and garlic and stir-fry for 6-8 minutes or until the mixture has lost most of its moisture and is fairly dry. Add the palm sugar and stir fry for a further few minutes until the sugar begins to caramelize and darken. Add the pork and scallops and stir fry for a further 8-10 minutes or until the mixture is thick and sticky.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[Remove the sauce from the heat and place in a food processor. Pulse several times until the mixture is coarsely blended. Stir in the fish and soy sauces and pepper.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[To store XO sauce, place it in a jar or bowl and cover with a thin layer of vegetable oil. XO sauce can be stored in the fridge for up to 2 weeks.]]></step>
<step><![CDATA[To use XO sauce in cooking, add several spoonfuls to your wok when stir-frying and along with a few extra splashes of soy sauce.]]></step>
&gt;</directions>
<ingredients xmlns:php="http://php.net/xsl">
        <serves/>
        <group>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>125</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[dried scallops (colpoy)]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>150</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[pork belly]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>50</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[dried shrimp]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>15-20</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[dried Thai bird's eye chilies]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[stemmed and deseeded]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>200</quantity>
            <measurement>ml</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[oil]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>20</quantity>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[shallots]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[thai]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>15</quantity>
            <measurement>cloves</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[garlic]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[minced]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>45</quantity>
            <measurement>g</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[palm sugar]]></name>
            <preparation><![CDATA[grated]]></preparation>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>3</quantity>
            <measurement>Tbsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[fish sauce]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity>4</quantity>
            <measurement>Tbsp</measurement>
            <name><![CDATA[soy sauce]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
          <ingredient>
            <quantity/>
            <measurement/>
            <name><![CDATA[freshly ground black pepper]]></name>
            <preparation/>
          </ingredient>
        </group>
      </ingredients>
</recipe>
